

# MATTIA CANCLINI

AUTOMATION AND CONTROL ENGINEER

#### **DATI ANAGRAFICI**

Nato a SONDRIO(SO), ITALIA, 16/05/1998 Residente in VIA SASSELLO 6 - 23032 BORMIO (SO)

# CONTATTI

- **\** +39 334 85 65 762
- <u> mattiacanclini@icloud.com</u>
- m www.linkedin.com/in/mattia-canclini

# **SOFT SKILLS**

Adattamento
Problem Solving
Motivazione
Resistenza allo stress
Capacità di lavorare in team
Team Leading
Organizzazione
Creatività
Attenzione ai dettagli
Flessibilità

### **PASSIONI**

Tecnologia Fotografia Design e Grafica Modellazione 3D

# **ATTIVITÀ SOCIALE**

#### dal 2021 ad OGGI

Volontario e consigliere AVIS Comunale Bormio

# dal 2018 ad 2022

Presidente Gioventù Pedenosso APS

# ALTRE ATTIVITÀ LAVORATIVE

Fotografo ad eventi tradizionali e manifestazioni sportive di rilevanza locale e nazionale

2021 - 2022

Ufficio accrediti Bormio FIS World Cup

Autorizzo il trattamento dei dati come da vostra informativa ai sensi del Regolamento Europeo 679/2016.
16/05/2024 Walko Cuclui

### **PROFILO**

Dopo aver ottenuto il diploma superiore di tecnico elettronico nel 2017 ho continuato gli studi al Politecnico di Milano. Li ho conseguito nel 2023 la Laurea Magistrale in Ingegneria dell'Automazione e del Controllo discutendo la mia Tesi "Uncertainty-Aware Motion Planning for a Robotic Manipulator in Vineyard Environments".

Durante la mia attività di ricerca ho avuto modo di approfondire le più avanzate tecniche di pathplanning e di acquisire competenze di programmazione con ROS.

Negli stessi anni ho maturato importanti esperienze lavorative, prima nell'industria farmaceutica per un prestigiosa multinazionale e poi nel settore del riciclaggio della plastica in un'azienda leader del mercato.

Oggi mi occupo di Systems Safety all'interno del team di Flight Control Systems in Leonardo Flicotteri

Appassionato di ingegneria, robotica e programmazione, trovo equilibrio nell'espressione creativa attraverso la fotografia e la grafica.

Sono convinto che la combinazione di competenze tecniche e sensibilità artistica mi renda un professionista pronto ad affrontare sfide intriganti, apportando un valore distintivo a qualsiasi contesto lavorativo

## **ESPERIENZE PROFESSIONALI**

#### da 05/2024 ad OGGI

Leonardo S.p.a. Divisione Elicotteri Cascina Costa di Samarate (VA) - Italia Garantire i requisiti di sicurezza e la certificazione per i Sistemi di Controllo di Volo, assicurare tolleranza ai guasti e ridondanza, definizione di test di volo e analisi dei dati. Contratto a tempo indeterminato - Flight Control System Engineer

#### da 07/2022 a 05/2024

Stelvio Automation s.r.l. Tirano (SO) - Italia || Previero s.r.l. Anzano del Parco (CO) - Italia Sviluppo software per Automazione industriale Contratto di Apprendistato - Ingegnere dell'Automazione

#### 06/2015 - 08/2015 | 06/2016 - 08/2016 | 07/2017 - 08/2017

Baxter S.p.A. || BiEffe Medital S.p.A. Grosotto (SO) - Italia Stage (2015), Contratto a tempo determinato (2016, 2017)

Collaboratore alla progettazione / automazione impianti industriali. Settore Farmaceutico

#### **ISTRUZIONE**

04/05/2023 - LAUREA MAGISTRALE IN AUTOMATION AND CONTROL ENGINEERING - INGEGNERIA DELL'AUTOMAZIONE presso POLITECNICO DI MILANO

22/07/2020 - LAUREA DI PRIMO LIVELLO IN INGEGNERIA DELL'AUTOMAZIONE presso POLITECNICO DI MILANO

11/07/2017 - Diploma di maturità: TECNICA INDUSTRIALE articolazione ELETTRONICA presso ISTITUTO DI ISTRUZIONE SUPERIORE ENEA MATTEI (SONDRIO - ITALIA)

#### PROGETTI ED ESPERIENZE ACCADEMICHE

05/2023 - Tesi di Laurea Magistrale: "UNCERTAINTY-AWARE MOTION PLANNING FOR A ROBOTIC MANIPULATOR IN VINEYARD ENVIRONMENTS".

06/2022 - Automation and Control Laboratory Project: "Magnetic levitation".

01/2022 - Safety in Automation Systems Project: "Hydropower System Hazard Analisys".

07/2020 - Passion in Action: MATLAB/SIMULINK per l'analisi e il progetto di sistemi di controllo.

# **CERTIFICAZIONI**

# 06/2018

National Instrument Milano - Italia

Certified LabVIEW Associated Developer

#### LINGUE STRANIERE

# INGLESE UK

09/09/2020 TOEFL 06/2016 Cambridge English Level 1 Certificate in ESOL international First Level B2

#### **CONOSCENZE INFORMATICHE**

## SETTORE INGEGNERISTICO

MATLAB
LabVIEW
Siemens TIA Portal
Fusion360

O O O

#### **PROGRAMMAZIONE**

#### OFFICE

Word - Pages Excel - Numbers PowerPoint - Keynote



#### GRAFICA

 Adobe

 Photoshop
 0

 Lightroom
 0

 Indesign
 0

 Illustrator
 0

 After Effects
 0
 0

 Maxon CINEMA4D
 0
 0

#### WEBDESIGN

HTML/CSS PHP



eCV: https://mattiacanclini.github.io/it-IT/









# MATTIA CANCLINI

AUTOMATION AND CONTROL ENGINEER

#### **PERSONAL DATA**

Born in SONDRIO(SO), ITALY, 16/05/1998 Resident in VIA SASSELLO 6 - 23032 BORMIO (SO)

#### **CONTACTS**

- **4** +39 334 85 65 762
- <u> mattiacanclini@icloud.com</u>
- m www.linkedin.com/in/mattia-canclini

# **SOFT SKILLS**

Adaptability	
Problem Solving	
Motivation	
Stress Resistance	
Teamwork	
Team Leading	
Organization	
Creativity	
Care for Detail	
Flessibility	

### **PASSIONS**

Technology Photography Graphic 3D Modeling

#### **SOCIAL ACTIVITIES**

#### from 2021 to TODAY

Volunteer and board member of AVIS Comunale Bormio

# from 2018 to 2022

President of Gioventù Pedenosso APS

# OTHER WORKING **EXPERIENCES**

Photographer at traditional events and sporting events of local and national relevance.

2021 - 2022

Accreditation office Bormio FIS World Cup

I authorize the processing of my personal data in accordance with your privacy policy under the European Regulation 679/2016. Wollo owlun 16/05/2024

### **PROFILE**



After obtaining my high school diploma in electronics in 2017, I pursued further studies at Politecnico di Milano. There, I earned a Master's degree in Automation and Control Engineering in 2023, defending my thesis on "Uncertainty-Aware Motion Planning for a Robotic Manipulator in Vineyard Environments.

Throughout my research activities, I delved into advanced path-planning techniques and acquired programming skills with ROS (Robot Operating System).

In parallel, I gained significant work experience, initially in the pharmaceutical industry for a prestigious multinational company and later in the plastic recycling sector for a market-leading

Today, I am responsible for Systems Safety within the Flight Control Systems team at Leonardo Helicopters.

Passionate about engineering, robotics, and programming, I find balance through creative expression in photography and graphics.

I am convinced that the combination of technical expertise and artistic sensibility makes me a professional ready to tackle intriguing challenges, bringing distinctive value to any work environment.

#### **WORK**

#### from 05/2024 to TODAY

Leonardo S.p.a. - Helicopters division Cascina Costa di Samarate (VA) - Italy Ensure system safety requirements and certification for Flight Control Systems, evaluate fault tolerance and redundancy, support malfunction flight tests, and analyze flight data. permanent contract - Flight Control System Engineer

#### from 07/2022 to 05/2024

Stelvio Automation s.r.l. Tirano (SO) - Italy | Previero s.r.l. Anzano del Parco (CO) - Italy Software development for industrial automation apprenticeship contract - Automation Engineer

#### 06/2015 - 08/2015 | 06/2016 - 08/2016 | 07/2017 - 08/2017

Baxter S.p.A. || BiEffe Medital S.p.A. Grosotto (SO) - Italy School-Work Apprenticeship (2015), fixed term contract (2016, 2017) Industrial plant automation and design collaborator. Pharmaceuticals Sector

#### **EDUCATION**

04/05/2023 - Master Degree in AUTOMATION AND CONTROL ENGINEERING -INGEGNERIA DELL'AUTOMAZIONE at POLITECNICO DI MILANO - Milan (Italy)

22/07/2020 - BECHELOR DEGREE IN AUTOMATION ENGINEERING at POLITECNICO DI MILANO - Milan (Italv)

11/07/2017 - High school leaving qualification - Electronic Technician at ISTITUTO DI ISTRUZIONE SUPERIORE ENEA MATTEI (Sondrio - Italy)

#### PROJECTS AND ACADEMIC EXPERIENCES

05/2023 - Master's thesis: "UNCERTAINTY-AWARE MOTION PLANNING FOR A ROBOTIC MANIPULATOR IN VINEYARD ENVIRONMENTS".

06/2022 - Automation and Control Laboratory Project: "Magnetic levitation"

01/2022 - Safety in Automation Systems Project: "Hydropower System Hazard Analisys".

07/2020 - Passion in Action: MATLAB/SIMULINK foor the analysis and design of control systems.

#### CERTIFICATES

# 06/2018

National Instrument Milano - Italy

Certified LabVIEW Associated Developer

#### **LINGUAGES**

# INGLESE UK

09/09/2020 TOEFL 06/2016 Cambridge English Level 1 Certificate in ESOL international First Level B2

#### SOFTWARE KNOWLEDGE

#### **ENGINEERING** MATLAB LabVIEW • • • • 0 Siemens TIA Portal • • • • 0 Fusion360 • • 0 0 0 CODING C++• • • • 0 ROS • • • • 0 JS • • • 0

OFFICE Word - Pages Excel - Numbers PowerPoint - Keynote



#### **GRAPHIC**

Adobe Photoshop • • • • 0 Liahtrooom • • • • 0 Indesign Illustrator • • • • 0 After Effects • • 0 0 0 Maxon CINEMA4D • • • 0 0

#### WEBDESIGN

HTML/CSS PHP





eCV: https://mattiacanclini.github.io







